我杀了小天狼星布莱克！
I killed Sirius Black！
他回来了
He's back.
《哈利波特与混血王子》
警方仍在进一步调查…
The police are continuing with the investigation…
千禧桥坍塌事件
…into the cause of the Millennium Bridge disaster.
警方搜寻幸存者期间，交通一度暂停
Traffic has been halted as police search for survivors.
事故现场周边区域仍处于戒备状态
The surrounding area remains closed.
市长呼吁伦敦市民保持冷静…
The mayor has urged Londoners to remain calm…
“哈利·波特”
「Harry Potter.」
哈利·波特是谁？
Who's Harry Potter？
哦，谁也不是
Oh，no one.
可能是某个呆子吧
Bit of a tosser，really.
你的报纸怪怪的
Funny，that paper of yours.
前几天晚上，我敢发誓看到照片里的人动了
Couple nights ago，I could've sworn I saw a picture move.
- 真的？ - 我估计是干活累得看花眼了
- Really？- Thought I was going around the twist.
- 嘿，我在想… - 11点，我那会下班
- Hey，I was wondering… - Eleven。That's when I get off.
到时候你可以跟我 慢慢讲讲这个呆瓜哈利·波特
You can tell me all about that tosser Harry Potter.
你这个夏天可是大胆得很啊，哈利
You've been reckless this summer，Harry.
我喜欢坐坐地铁
I like riding around on trains.
免得胡思乱想
Takes my mind off things.
看着不怎么招人喜欢，对吧？
Rather unpleasant to behold，isn't it？
说实话，这倒是个挺惊险的故事
The tale is thrilling，if I say so myself.
可现在不是说故事的时候
But now is not the time to tell it.
搭着我的手臂
Take my arm.
照我说的做
Do as I say.
我刚刚是不是幻影移形了？
I just Apparated，didn't I？
是的，要我说，还很是成功
Indeed。Quite successfully too，I might add.
绝大多数人第一次都吐了
Most people vomit the first time.
真让人想不通（反话）
I can't imagine why.
欢迎来到美丽的巴德莱·巴伯顿村
Welcome to the charming village of Budleigh Babberton.
哈利，我猜，现在你正奇怪 我为什么要带你来这里
Harry，I assume，right about now，you're wondering why I brought you here.
对吧？
Am I right？
老实说，教授，经历这么多年 我差不多已经不想了
Actually，sir，after all these years，I just sort of go with it.
拔出魔杖，哈利
Wands out，Harry.
霍拉斯？
Horace？
梅林的胡子啊！ （意为我的老天爷！）
Merlin's beard！
你也没必要非得戳穿我啊，阿不思
No need to disfigure me，Albus.
我不得不说，你这椅子变得很是成功，霍拉斯
Well，I must say you make a very convincing armchair，Horace.
那都是表面功夫做的足，里子那是天然的（大肚子） 我哪儿露馅了？
It's all in the upholstery。I come by the stuffing naturally。What gave me away？
龙血
Dragon's blood.
- 哦 - 哦，对了，我给你们介绍
- Oh。- Oh，yes，introductions.
哈利，来来见见 我的这位老朋友，老同事…
Harry，I'd like you to meet an old friend and colleague of mine…
霍拉斯·斯拉格霍恩
…Horace Slughorn.
霍拉斯…
Horace…
我知道他是谁
…well，you know who this is.
哈利·波特
Harry Potter.
你这房间布置得如此有舞台效果 怎么回事，霍拉斯？
What's with all the theatrics，Horace？
你不会还在等别的客人吧？
You weren't，by any chance，waiting for someone else？
客人？我可不知道你什么意思
Someone else？I'm sure I don't know what you mean.
好了，食死徒想招纳我，都一年多了
All right，the Death Eaters have been trying to recruit me for over a year.
你知道那是什么样的日子吗？
Do you know what that's like？
我不能拒绝太多次 所以在任何一个地方我都呆不过一周
You can only say no so many times，so I never stay anywhere more than a week.
这家的麻瓜主人去加那利群岛度假了
Muggles who own this are in the Canary Islands.
我想，我们最好还是把这里收拾一下 不介意吧？
Well，I think we should put it back in order for them，don't you？Mind.
真是有趣
That was fun.
- 介意我用下洗手间吗？ - 当然不介意
- Do you mind if I use the loo？- No，of course.
别以为我不知道你为什么来，阿不思
Don't think I don't know why you're here，Albus.
答案还是“不” 确定以及肯定的不
The answer's still no。Absolutely and unequivocally，no.
你长得很像你父亲
You're very like your father.
- 除了这双眼睛，很像… - 我母亲的眼睛，我知道
- Except for the eyes。You have your… - My mother's eyes。Yeah.
莉莉，伶俐的莉莉，你的母亲很聪慧
Lily。Lovely Lily。She was exceedingly bright，your mother.
要是再考虑到她还是个麻瓜出生 就更是了不起了
Even more impressive when one considers she was Muggle-born.
我一个最好的朋友也是麻瓜出生 是全年级最棒的
One of my best friends is Muggle-born。Best in our year.
请不要以为我有偏见，没有，绝对没有
Please don't think I'm prejudiced。No，no.
你母亲绝对是我最喜欢的学生之一 看，她就在那儿
Your mother was one of my absolute favorites。Look，there she is.
前排
Right at the front.
全是我的，所有人
All mine。Each and every one.
全是我以前的学生
Ex-students，I mean.
你认出巴拿巴斯·古费了吧 他是预言家日报的主编
You recognize Barnabas Cuffe，editor of The Daily Prophet.
要是对当天的新闻有什么看法 我就可以派猫头鹰
Always takes my owl，should I wish to register an opinion…
给他捎个信
…on the news of the day.
格韦诺格·琼斯 霍利黑德哈比队队长
Gwenog Jones，captain of the Holyhead Harpies.
只要我想，随时都能拿到免费门票
Free tickets whenever I want them.
自然了，我已经很久没有看比赛了
Of course，I haven't been to a match in some time.
哦，对了
Ah，yes.
雷古勒斯·布莱克
Regulus Black.
你肯定认识他的哥哥 小天狼星，前几周刚刚过世
You no doubt know of his older brother Sirius。Died a few weeks ago.
布莱克全家都是我教的 除了小天狼星
I taught the whole Black family，except Sirius.
真是可惜，他是个很有天赋的孩子
It's a shame。Talented boy.
雷古勒斯一来，我就看好他了 当然，如果兄弟一起，就更完美了
I got Regulus when he came along，of course，but I'd have liked the set.
霍拉斯？
Horace？
不介意我带走这个吧？
Do you mind if I take this？
- 我很喜欢这些针织的款式 - 当然，拿去吧，可你不会现在就走吧？
- I do love knitting patterns。- Yes，of course。But you're not leaving？
事情已成定局时，我还是知道的 真是太可惜了
I think I know a lost cause when I see one。Regrettable.
如果能劝你同我一起回霍格沃兹…
I would have considered it a personal triumph…
我自然将不胜荣幸
…had you consented to return to Hogwarts。Oh，well.
你跟波特一样，可都是可遇不可求啊
You're like my friend Mr。Potter here，one of a kind.
好了，再会，霍拉斯
Well，bye-bye，Horace.
再见
Bye.
好吧，我答应
All right。I'll do it.
我要原来梅乐思教授的办公室 我原来的那个像厕所
But I want Professor Merrythought's old office，not the water closet I had before.
我还要加薪！这年头疯事不少！
And I expect a raise。These are mad times we live in。Mad！
确实不少
They are indeed.
教授，刚才到底是怎么回事？
Sir，exactly what was all that about？
你有天赋，有名气，有力量 有霍拉斯重视的一切
You are talented，famous and powerful。Everything Horace values.
斯拉格霍恩教授 会想将你收入门下，哈利
Professor Slughorn is gonna try to collect you，Harry.
你会是他所有门徒中最闪耀的
You would be his crowning jewel.
因为你，所以他才回霍格沃兹 对我们来说，他回来也很重要
That's why he's returning to Hogwarts。And it's crucial he should return.
恐怕我已经搅了 你这个原本美妙的夜晚，哈利
I fear I may have stolen a wondrous night from you，Harry.
那位姑娘，说真的，可真是漂亮
She was，truthfully，very pretty，the girl.
没事，教授，我明天回去 找点借口跟她解释就好了
It's all right，sir。I'll go back tomorrow，make some excuse.
你今晚可回不了小惠金区，哈利
Oh，you'll not be returning to Little Whinging tonight，Harry.
可是，海德薇怎么办？还有我的行李？
But，sir，what about Hedwig？And my trunk？
都等着你呢
Both are waiting for you.
海德薇
Hedwig.
妈？
Mum？
金妮，什么事？
Ginny，what is it？
哈利什么时候来的？
I was only wondering when Harry got here.
- 什么？哈利？哪个哈利？ - 当然是哈利·波特了
- What？Harry？Harry who？- Harry Potter，of course.
哈利·波特要是在我家，我会不知道吗？
I think I'd know if Harry Potter was in my house，wouldn't I？
- 他的行李就放在厨房呢，还有猫头鹰 - 不会吧，亲爱的，我可不信
- His trunk's in the kitchen，and his owl。- No，dear，I seriously doubt that.
哈利？有谁说“哈利”了？
Harry？Did someone say 「Harry」？
我说的，多事鬼，他在楼上吗？
Me，nosy。Is he up there with you？
当然没，我死党要是在我屋，我会不知道？
Of course not。I'd know if my best friend was in my room，wouldn't I？
- 是猫头鹰在叫吗？ - 你没见到他，对吧？
- Is that an owl？- You haven't seen him，have you？
他貌似在这屋里游荡呢
He's wandering about the house.
- 真的？ - 真的
- Really？- Really.
哈利！
Harry！
真是个惊喜
What a lovely surprise.
你怎么不先跟我们说一声？
Why didn't you let us know you were coming？
- 我不知道要来，是邓不利多 - 哦，他啊
- I didn't know。Dumbledore。- Oh，that man.
他就是爱乱来 可要是没了他，我们可怎么办
But then，what would we do without him？
你嘴角有点牙膏
Got a bit of toothpaste.
你什么时候到的？
So when did you get here？
没几天
A few days ago.
不过在那之前，我犹豫了一阵子
Though for a while，I wasn't sure I was coming.
老妈上星期有点神经过敏
Mum sort of lost it last week.
说我和金妮回霍格沃兹也没用
Said Ginny and I had no business going back to Hogwarts.
说那里很危险
That it's too dangerous.
- 拜托 - 不止她一个
- Oh，come on。- She's not alone.
就连我爸妈，他们即使是麻瓜 也知道发生了不好的事情
Even my parents，and they're Muggles，know something bad's happening.
不管怎样吧，老爸插话了 说老妈是一时糊涂
Anyway，Dad stepped in，told her she was being barmy…
劝了是有几天 不过最后她总算回心转意
…and it took a few days，but she came around.
我们说的可是霍格沃兹 是邓不利多，还有哪里更安全？
But this is Hogwarts we're talking about。It's Dumbledore。What could be safer？
最近有很多风言风语…
There's been a lot of talk recently that…
说邓不利多老了
…Dumbledore's got a bit old.
胡说，他才…
Rubbish！Well，he's only…
他得多大了？
What is he？
一百五十岁？差不离了吧
Hundred and fifty？Give or take a few years.
西茜！你不能这么做！ 不能相信他！
Cissy！You can't do this！He can't be trusted！
黑魔王信任他
The Dark Lord trusts him.
黑魔王被蒙蔽了
The Dark Lord's mistaken.
退下吧，虫尾巴
Run along，Wormtail.
我知道，我不该来这
I know I ought not to be here.
黑魔王陛下禁止我谈论此事
The Dark Lord himself forbade me to speak of this.
如果黑魔王不准你谈，你就不该谈
If the Dark Lord has forbidden it，you ought not to speak.
放下，贝拉，别人的东西，不要乱动
Put it down，Bella。We mustn't touch what isn't ours.
巧的是，我知道你现在的处境，纳西莎
As it so happens，I'm aware of your situation，Narcissa.
你？
You？
黑魔王把这件事告诉了你？
The Dark Lord told you？
你妹妹质疑我
Your sister doubts me.
可以理解，这么多年，我演的太好了
Understandable。Over the years I've played my part well.
好得骗倒了有史以来最伟大的巫师之一
So well，I've deceived one of the greatest wizards of all time.
邓不利多是一名伟大的巫师 只有蠢材才会怀疑
Dumbledore is a great wizard。Only a fool would question it.
我不怀疑你，西弗勒斯
I don't doubt you，Severus.
你该感到荣耀，西茜，德拉科也是
You should be honored，Cissy。As should Draco.
他还只是个孩子
He's just a boy.
我无法动摇黑魔王的意志
I can't change the Dark Lord's mind.
但我可以暗中帮助德拉科
But it might be possible for me to help Draco.
- 西弗勒斯 - 发誓
- Severus。- Swear to it.
立一个牢不可破的誓言
Make the Unbreakable Vow.
其他的都是空话
It's just empty words.
什么“我会尽力”了
He'll give it his best effort.
可到了真正关键的时候…
But when it matters most…
他就只会滑回自己的蛇洞
…he'll just slither back into his hole.
懦夫
Coward.
拿出魔仗
Take out your wand.
你…
Will you…
西弗勒斯·斯内普…
…Severus Snape…
能否看顾德拉科·马尔福…
…watch over Draco Malfoy…
助他完成黑魔王的嘱托？
…as he attempts to fulfill the Dark Lord's wishes？
我会
I will.
你，能否尽你所能…
And will you，to the best of your ability…
保护他，免受伤害？
…protect him from harm？
我会
I will.
如果德拉科失败…
And if Draco should fail…
你，能否继续完成…
…will you yourself carry out the deed…
黑魔王所托未竟之事？
…the Dark Lord has ordered Draco to perform？
我会
I will.
瞧一瞧，看一看了，新到的昏迷花糖！
Step up！Step up！We've got Fainting Fancies！
鼻血牛扎糖！
Nosebleed Nougats！
- 若想准时下课… - 就用呕吐片！
- And just in time for school… - Puking Pastilles！
- 吐到坩埚里哦，小帅哥 - 吐到坩埚里哦，小帅哥
- Into the cauldron，handsome。- Into the cauldron，handsome.
- 隐身烟雾弹，秘鲁进口的 - 这可是我们的摇钱树
- Peruvian Instant Darkness Powder。- A real money spinner，that.
脱身必备哦
Handy if you need to make a quick getaway.
- 好了，女士们 - 好了，女士们
- Hello，ladies。- Hello，ladies.
- 想试试迷魂药？ - 效果确实不错哦
- Love potions，eh？- Yeah，they really do work.
不过话说回来，据我们掌握的情报 小妹，你自己就很玩得转嘛
Then again，the way we hear it，sis，you're doing just fine on your own.
什么意思？
Meaning？
你不是在和迪安·托马斯好着吗？
Are you not currently dating Dean Thomas？
不关你们的事
It's none of your business.
这个多少钱？
How much for this？
- 五加隆 - 五加隆
- Five Galleons。- Five Galleons.
- 卖给我多少钱？ - 五加隆
- How much for me？- Five Galleons.
我是你们弟弟
I'm your brother.
- 那就十加隆 - 那就十加隆
- Ten Galleons。- Ten Galleons.
好了，我们走吧
Come on，let's go.
嗨，罗恩
Hi，Ron.
乔治和弗雷德怎么办到的？ 半条对角巷的店都关了
How are Fred and George doing it？Half the Alley's closed down.
弗雷德觉得，在这种时候 大家更需要点笑声
Fred reckons people need a laugh these days.
我觉得他说的对
I reckon he's right.
不会吧
Oh，no.
大家的魔杖都是从奥利凡德买的
Everyone got their wands from Ollivander's.
哈利？
Harry？
我是看花眼，还是那真是德拉科和他老妈…
Is it me，or do Draco and Mummy look like two people…
鬼鬼祟祟不想被人看见？
…who don't want to be followed？
唱唱反调
Quibbler.
这个侏儒蒲真可爱，他们会在节礼日唱歌，你知道的吧
He's lovely。They've been known to sing on Boxing Day，you know.
- 来份唱唱反调？ - 哦，谢谢
- Quibbler？- Oh，please.
- 搔扰虻是什么？ - 那是一种隐形生物
- What's a Wrackspurt？- They're invisible creatures.
他们会钻进你耳朵，搞得你脑子一团糟
They float in your ears and make your brain go fuzzy.
唱唱反调
Quibbler.
你们说，德拉科要那个诡异的橱柜干嘛？
So，what was Draco doing with that weird-looking cabinet？
还有那群人，都谁啊？
And who were all those people？
你看不出来吗？ 那是某种仪式，入会仪式
Don't you see？It was a ceremony，an initiation.
别说了，哈利，我知道你想说什么
Stop it，Harry。I know where you're going.
事实摆在眼前，他是他们的一份子
It's happened。He's one of them.
谁们？
One of what？
哈利觉得，德拉科·马尔福是食死徒
Harry is under the impression Draco Malfoy is now a Death Eater.
少扯了
You're barking.
神秘人要他能干什么？
What would You-Know-Who want with Malfoy？
那你们说，他在博金-博克干嘛？挑家具？
Well，then what's he doing in Borgin and Burkes？Browsing for furniture？
怪人逛怪店，见怪不怪
It's a creepy shop。He's a creepy bloke.
他爸是食死徒，他也是，这才说得通
Look，his father is a Death Eater。It only makes sense.
赫敏也亲眼看到了
Hermione saw it with her own eyes.
我说过了，我不知道那是什么
I told you，I don't know what I saw.
我得去透透气
I need some air.
别担心，等到了霍格沃兹，我们再收拾
Don't worry。When we get to Hogwarts，we'll sort it out.
- 怎么回事？布雷斯 - 不知道
- What was that？Blaise？- Don't know.
别紧张兮兮的 可能只是一些一年级小鬼在瞎闹
Relax，boys。It's probably just a first-year messing around.
来了，德拉科，坐下 马上就到霍格沃兹了
Come on，Draco。Sit down。We'll be at Hogwarts soon.
霍格沃兹 找这么个借口去上学，真可悲
Hogwarts。What a pathetic excuse for a school.
要是我还得在那上两年学
I'd pitch myself off the Astronomy Tower…
我非得跳天文塔自杀不可
…if I had to continue for another two years.
你这话什么意思啊？
What's that supposed to mean？
这么说吧，明年 你就看不到我在魔咒课上浪费生命了
Let's just say you won't see me wasting my time in Charms class next year.
很好笑吗，布雷斯？
Amused，Blaise？
那就看是谁笑到最后
We'll see just who's laughing in the end.
你们两个先走 我还要检查下一点东西
You two go on。I wanna check something.
哈利在哪？
Where's Harry？
他可能已经上站台了，走吧
He's probably already on the platform。Come on.
难道你妈咪没告诉你 偷听很没礼貌吗，波特？
Didn't Mummy ever tell you it was rude to eavesdrop，Potter？
统统石化！
Petrificus Totalus.
你还没学会擦干口水，她就死了
…she was dead before you could wipe the drool off your chin.
这一脚是替我父亲踢的 回伦敦旅行愉快
That's for my father。Enjoy your ride back to London.
咒立停
Finite.
- 你好啊，哈利 - 卢娜！
- Hello，Harry。- Luna！
- 你怎么知道我在这？ - 骚扰虻，你满脑子都是
- How'd you know where I was？- Wrackspurts。Your head's full of them.
真不好意思，害你也错过马车，卢娜
Sorry I made you miss the carriages，by the way，Luna.
没关系，感觉像是跟朋友散步
That's all right。It was like being with a friend.
我就是你朋友，卢娜
Oh，I am your friend，Luna.
真好
That's nice.
刚好，我找你们两个半天了
About time。I've been looking all over for you two.
好了，姓名？
Right。Names？
弗利维教授，你都认识我五年了
Professor Flitwick，you've known me for five years.
谁也不能例外，波特
No exceptions，Potter.
他们是谁？
Who are those people？
傲罗，负责安全保卫的
Aurors。For security.
这根藤条是干什么的？
What's this cane here，then？
这不是藤条，你个蠢货，是手杖
It's not a cane，you cretin。It's a walking stick.
那你准备拿这个干什么？
And what exactly would you be wanting with a…
这可以拿来当武器使
Could be construed as an offensive weapon.
没事了，费尔奇，我能替马尔福担保
It's all right，Mr。Filch。I can vouch for Mr。Malfoy.
这一脸够帅啊，波特
Nice face，Potter.
你希望我帮你治好吗？
Would you like me to fix it for you？
我个人觉得，你这样看着更不修边幅…
Personally，I think you look a bit more devil-may-care this way…
不过治不治由你
…but it's up to you.
那个，你以前治过鼻子吗？
Well，have you ever fixed a nose before？
没，脚趾头倒是治过一些 能差得到哪里去呢，对吧？
No，but I've done several toes，and how different are they，really？
嗯，好吧，那就试试
Um… Okay，yeah。Give it a go.
- 愈合如初 - 啊！
- Episkey。- Ah！
- 看起来怎么样？ - 异常得正常
- How do I look？- Exceptionally ordinary.
好极了
Brilliant.
别担心，他一会就到了
Don't worry。He'll be here in a minute.
你能不能别吃了？
Will you stop eating？
你最好的朋友不见了！
Your best friend is missing！
诶，回头看，小疯子
Oi。Turn around，you lunatic.
他又满身是血
He's covered in blood again.
- 他怎么老是浑身是血？ - 好像这回是他自己的血
- Why is it he's always covered in blood？- Looks like it's his own this time.
你去哪儿了？
Where have you been？
- 你的脸怎么了？ - 呆会再说
- What happened to your face？- Later.
我错过什么了吗？
What've I missed？
分院帽鼓励大伙，在这种乱世 要变得更勇敢坚强
Sorting Hat urged us all to be brave and strong in these troubled times.
它说得倒轻巧，是不？它不过是顶帽子
Easy for it to say，huh？It's a hat，isn't it？
各位晚上好
Very best of evenings to you all.
多谢
Thanks.
首先，我给大家介绍一下新教员
First off，let me introduce the newest member of our staff…
霍拉斯·斯拉格霍恩
…Horace Slughorn.
斯拉格霍恩教授，我在此荣幸地宣布…
Professor Slughorn，I'm happy to say…
已经同意回来继任魔药课教授
…has agreed to resume his old post as Potions Master.
与此同时，黑魔法防御课教授
Meanwhile，the post of Defense Against the Dark Arts…
将由斯内普教授担任
…will be taken by Professor Snape.
斯内普？
Snape？
如各位所知
Now，as you know…
每人在今晚入校前都被搜查
…each and every one of you was searched upon your arrival here tonight.
你们有权知道原因
And you have the right to know why.
从前，有个年轻人，他和你们一样
Once there was a young man，who，like you…
坐过这个大厅
…sat in this very hall…
走过这里的走廊，睡过这里的床铺
…walked this castle's corridors，slept under its roof.
他看起来和其他人没什么两样
He seemed to all the world a student like any other.
他的名字？
His name？
叫汤姆·里德尔
Tom Riddle.
如今，当然了
Today，of course…
世人只知道他的另一个名字
…he's known all over the world by another name.
正因此，此时此刻，我看着诸位
Which is why，as I stand looking out upon you all tonight…
想起来一个不争的事实
…I'm reminded of a sobering fact.
每天，每时
Every day，every hour…
甚至于就在这一刻，或许
…this very minute，perhaps…
黑暗势力就在试图侵入这城堡的高墙
…dark forces attempt to penetrate this castle's walls.
但最终，他们最致命的武器，还是你们
But in the end，their greatest weapon is you.
希望你们能好好想想
Just something to think about.
好了，上床去吧，晚安
Now，off to bed。Pip-pip.
这可真叫鼓舞人心
That was cheerful.
女士们，魔法史在楼上上课，不是楼下
History of Magic is upstairs，ladies，not down.
戴维斯！戴维斯（先生）！那里是女厕所
Mr。Davies！Mr。Davies！That is the girls' lavatory.
波特
Potter.
哦，不妙
Oh，this can't be good.
最近过的不错，对吧？
Enjoying ourselves，are we？
- 我早上没课 - 我发现了
- I had a free period this morning。- So I noticed.
我想你大概会考虑去上魔药课
I would think you would want to fill it with Potions.
又或者你已经不再想当傲罗了？
Or is it no longer your ambition to become an Auror？
我是想，可我得先在O.W.L考试里拿“优秀”
It was，but I was told I had to get an 「Outstanding」 in my O.W.L.
确实，斯内普教授教魔药的时候是如此
So you did，when Professor Snape was teaching Potions.
但是，斯拉格霍恩教授会很乐意收
However，Professor Slughorn is perfectly happy to accept N.E.W.T。s students…
得“良好”的N.W.E.T.s学生
…with 「Exceeds Expectations.」
太好了，嗯…
Brilliant。Um…
- 那，我这就过去 - 很好，很好
- Well，I'll head there straightaway。- Oh，good，good.
波特，把韦斯莱也带上 他看起来太快活了
Potter，take Weasley with you。He looks far too happy over there.
我不想上魔药课
I don't wanna take Potions.
魁地奇球员选拔就要开始了 我还得多练练呢
This is Quidditch trials coming up。I need to practice.
在准备阶段关注细节…
Attention to detail in the preparation…
是所有计划成功的先觉条件
…is the prerequisite of all planning.
哈利，孩子，我都开始担心了 我看你还带了朋友过来嘛
Harry，my boy，I was beginning to worry。We've brought someone with us，I see.
我叫罗恩·韦斯莱，教授
Ron Weasley，sir.
我魔药学得糟透了 说实话，要我煎药对别人也是威胁
But I'm dead awful at Potions，a menace，actually.
- 所以我… - 胡说，我们上完课才知道
- I'm gonna… - Nonsense，we'll sort you out.
哈利的朋友就是我的朋友 把书都拿出来
Any friend of Harry's is a friend of mine。Get your books out.
我的书还没到，罗恩也没书
I haven't actually got my book yet，and nor has Ron.
那就去壁橱里找找吧
Get what you want from the cupboard.
刚才我们说到，今早 我准备了一些汤剂
Now，as I was saying，I prepared some concoctions this morning.
有谁知道这些都是什么吗？
Any ideas what these might be？
- 很好，这位…？ - 格兰杰，教授
- Yes，Miss… - Granger，sir.
那锅是吐真剂，可以令人吐露真相
That one there is Veritaserum。It's a truth-telling serum.
那锅是复方汤剂
And that would be Polyjuice Potion.
熬制起来相当复杂
It's terribly tricky to make.
这锅，是迷情剂
And this is Amortentia…
世上最强效的迷魂药
…the most powerful love potion in the world.
据说，它因人而异，会散发出 最吸引当事人的气味
It's rumored to smell differently to each person according to what attracts them.
比如，我闻到的是…
For example，I smell…
刚刚割过的草坪 崭新的羊皮纸，和…
…freshly mown grass，and new parchment，and…
留兰香味牙膏
…spearmint toothpaste.
迷情剂不能产生真正的爱情 因为爱情不可能仿造
Amortentia doesn't create actual love。That would be impossible.
但它确实可以令人产生迷恋
But it does cause a powerful infatuation or obsession.
因此，这可能是这个房间里最危险的魔药
And for that reason，it is probably the most dangerous potion in this room.
教授，你还没说，那个锅里的是什么
Sir？You haven't told us what's in that one.
哦，对了
Oh，yes.
女士们先生们，你们所看到的
What you see before you，ladies and gentlemen…
是一种神奇的药水，叫福灵剂
…is a curious little potion known as Felix Felicis.
不过，人们通常都称之为…
But it is more commonly referred to as…
- 幸运水 - 正是，格兰杰小姐，幸运水
- Liquid luck。- Yes，Miss Granger。Liquid luck.
制作过程极度繁复 稍有差错，后果便不堪设想
Desperately tricky to make，disastrous should you get it wrong.
只需一小口，你的所有努力 便能轻而易举地成功
One sip and you will find that all of your endeavors succeed.
至少，在药效过去之前是如此
At least until the effects wear off.
所以呢，今天我就拿它做奖品
So this is what I offer each of you today.
这一小瓶的幸运水，将奖励给…
One tiny vial of liquid luck to the student who，in the hour that remains…
能在一个小时内，熬制出生死水（强效安眠药）的学生
…manages to brew an acceptable Draught of Living Death…
所需的材料都罗列在书本的第十页
…the recipes for which can be found on page 10 of your books.
不过我要提醒大家，在此之前 只有一名学生
I should point out，however，only once did a student manage to brew a potion…
熬出了合格的生死水，赢得这个奖励
…of sufficient quality to claim this prize.
话虽如此，还是祝各位好运！
Nevertheless，good luck to you all.
现在就正式开始吧
Let the brewing commence.
（此书乃混血王子之财产）
（切碎跳跳豆 用刀侧碾碎 更易出汁）
你怎么办到的？
How did you do that？
你用碾的，别切
You crush it。Don't cut it.
不对，书上写的明明白白，要切
No。The instructions specifically say to cut.
不用，真的
No，really.
梅林的胡子啊！真是完美
Merlin's beard！It is perfect.
太完美了，我敢说只要一滴 就能让全班的人都睡死过去
So perfect I daresay one drop would kill us all.
好了，如我所承诺的
So here we are，then，as promised.
奖励福灵剂一瓶
One vial of Felix Felicis.
恭喜
Congratulations.
好好使用
Use it well.
哈利，你收到信了，进来吧
Harry，you got my message。Come in.
最近怎样？
How are you？
很好，教授
I'm fine，sir.
课还喜欢吗？
Enjoying your classes？
我知道斯拉格霍恩教授尤为喜欢你
I know Professor Slughorn is most impressed with you.
我想他是高估我的水平了
I think he overestimates my abilities，sir.
你真这么想？
Do you？
千真万确
Definitely.
你的课外活动如何啊？
What about your activities outside the classroom？
- 您什么意思？ - 我注意到…
- Sir？- Well，I notice you spend…
你经常和格兰杰小姐一起出入
…a great deal of time with Miss Granger.
所以忍不住猜测…
I can't help wondering…
哦，没，没有，她是很棒 我们也是朋友，但不是您猜的那样
Oh，no，no。I mean，she's brilliant，and we're friends，but，no.
敬请原谅，我这纯属好奇
Forgive me。I was merely being curious.
闲聊得够多的了
But enough chitchat.
我一定在奇怪，我今晚为什么要请你过来
You must be wondering why I summoned you here tonight.
答案就在这里
The answer lies here.
你所看到的这些都是记忆
What you are looking at are memories.
在这个小瓶里装的，就是关于伏地魔的…
In this case，pertaining to one individual，Voldemort…
或者我们可以称之为，汤姆·里德尔
…or，as he was known then，Tom Riddle.
这个小瓶里装的记忆
This vial contains the most particular memory…
就是我第一次见到他时候的情景
…of the day I first met him.
你要是愿意，我很希望你能看看
I'd like you to see it，if you would.
我得承认，接到你的来信我有些困惑 邓不利多先生
I admit some confusion upon receiving your letter，Mr。Dumbledore.
这么多年了，从来没有什么亲戚来看过汤姆
In all the years Tom's been here，he's never once had a family visitor.
其他孩子身上发生过一些事故，可怕的事故
There have been incidents with the other children。Nasty things.
汤姆，有人来看望你了
Tom，you have a visitor.
你过得怎么样，汤姆？
How do you do，Tom？
别碰
Don't.
- 你是医生，是不是？ - 不是
- You're the doctor，aren't you？- No.
我是教授
I am a professor.
我不信
I don't believe you.
她想让我去看病
She wants me looked at.
他们觉得我跟别人不一样
They think I'm different.
嗯，他们可能还真说对了
Well，perhaps they're right.
我没疯
I'm not mad.
霍格沃兹不是疯人院
Hogwarts is not a place for mad people.
霍格沃兹是所学校
Hogwarts is a school.
传授魔法的学校
A school of magic.
你能做一些事，对不对，汤姆？
You can do things，can't you，Tom？
一些别的孩子做不到的事
Things other children can't.
我不用碰，就能让东西动起来
I can make things move without touching them.
我不用教，就能让动物听我的话
I can make animals do what I want without training them.
如果有谁对我不好，我就能让他遭殃
I can make bad things happen to people who are mean to me.
我能伤害他们…
I can make them hurt…
只要我想
…if I want.
你是谁？
Who are you？
我跟你一样，汤姆
Well，I'm like you，Tom.
与众不同
I'm different.
证明给我看
Prove it.
你的衣柜里好像有些什么东西 想钻出来啊，汤姆
I think there's something in your wardrobe trying to get out，Tom.
霍格沃兹不容许偷窃
Thievery is not tolerated at Hogwarts，Tom.
在霍格沃兹，你不仅要学习如何使用魔法 还要学习如何控制魔法
At Hogwarts，you'll be taught not only how to use magic，but how to control it.
明白我的意思吗？
You understand me？
我还能和蛇说话
I can speak to snakes too.
是它们找到我的
They find me.
跟我说悄悄话
Whisper things.
这对像我这样的人来说，正常吗？
Is that normal for someone like me？
你当时知道吗，教授？
Did you know，sir？Then？
知道我刚见到了有史以来最邪恶的黑巫师？ 当然不知道
Did I know I'd just met the most dangerous dark wizard of all time？No.
就算我知道，我也…
If I had，I…
他在霍格沃兹的这些年里…
Over time，while here at Hogwarts…
汤姆·里德尔和一个老师走得特别近
…Tom Riddle grew close to one particular teacher.
猜猜看那个老师是谁？
Can you guess who that teacher might be？
你劝斯拉格霍恩教授回来 不止是教魔药课，对吧？
You didn't bring Professor Slughorn back simply to teach Potions，did you？
不，不止
No，I did not.
斯拉格霍恩教授有一样东西 是我迫切需要的
You see，Professor Slughorn possesses something I desire very dearly.
他自然也不会轻易地交出来
And he will not give it up easily.
你说他会想招我入门
You said Professor Slughorn would try to collect me.
是的
I did.
你想要我答应吗？
Do you want me to let him？
是的
Yes.
好了，嗯…
All right。Um…
今早，我们会进行几轮选拔
This morning，I'm gonna be putting you all through a few drills…
考核你们的实力
…just to assess your strengths.
请安静下！
Quiet！Please！
都闭嘴！
Shut it！
多谢，那个，然后…
Thanks。All right。Um…
就算你们去年是正式队员
Just because you made the team last year…
我不保证你们今年也是 这么说，明白了吗？
…does not guarantee you a spot this year。Is that clear？
很好
Good.
韦斯莱，别介意，好嘛？
No hard feelings，Weasley，all right？
介意？
Hard feelings？
我也要打守球手这个位置 真不是针对你
Yeah，I'll be going out for Keeper as well。It's nothing personal.
真的？以你这个头？
Really？Strapping guy like you？
你不觉得你更适合当击球手吗？
You've got more of a Beater's build，don't you think？
守球手要眼疾手快
Keepers need to be quick，agile.
哦，我还是想先试试运气
Oh，I like my chances.
话说，你能给我介绍介绍 你那朋友格兰杰吧？
Say，think you could introduce me to your friend Granger？
要能知名知姓就最好了 懂我的意思吗？
Wouldn't mind getting on a first-name basis，know what I mean？
加油，韦斯莱！
Come on，Weasley！
- 加油，罗恩！ - 上啊，韦斯莱！
- Come on，Ron！- Go on，Weasley！
- 上！韦斯莱！- 好 罗恩
- Go on，Weasley！- Yeah，Ron！
加油，考迈克！
Go on，Cormac！
加油，罗恩！
Come on，Ron！
加油啊，罗恩
Come on，Ron.
速速混淆
Confundus.
他真是太棒了！
Isn't he brilliant？
老实说，最后一个我真没想到能接住
I have to admit，I thought I was gonna miss that last one.
但愿考迈克别太难受
I hope Cormac's not taking it too hard.
他对你有点意思，赫敏，就那个考迈克
He's got a bit of a thing for you，Hermione。Cormac.
他可不讨人喜欢
He's vile.
你们听说过这个咒语吗？ 神锋无影？
Have you ever heard of this spell？Sectumsempra？
没听过
No，I haven't.
你要是还尊敬自己那么一点点 你就该把书上交
And if you had a shred of self-respect，you'd hand that book in.
想都别想，他现在可是尖子生
Not bloody likely。He's top of the class.
比你都强呢，赫敏 斯拉格霍恩都把他当天才了
He's even better than you，Hermione。Slughorn thinks he's a genius.
咋了？
What？
我想知道这书到底是谁的 给我看看
I'd like to know whose that book was。Let's have a look.
不给
No.
为什么不？
Why not？
这书的装订线都松了
The binding is fragile.
- 装订松了？ - 嗯
- The binding is fragile？- Yeah.
- 混血王子是谁？ - 谁？
- Who's the Half-Blood Prince？- Who？
这里是这么写的：“此书乃混血王子之财产”
That's what it says right here：「This book is property of the Half-Blood Prince.」
这么久了，你到哪都带着这本书 就差抱着它睡觉了
For weeks you carry around this book，practically sleep with it…
可你却一点都不想知道这人是谁？
… yet you have no desire to find out who he is？
我没说我不好奇 再说我还没到抱着它睡觉的地步
I didn't say I wasn't curious，and I don't sleep with it.
也也差不多了
Well，it's true.
我想睡前夜谈，你就只知道捧着本书看
I like a nice chat before I go to bed。Now all you do is read that bloody book.
简直跟赫敏第二过日子一样
It's just like being with Hermione.
我有些好奇，所以就去…
Well，I was curious，so I went to…
- 图书馆 - 然后呢？
- The library。- The library。And？
什么都没找到
And nothing.
无论什么地方 都没有提到过混血王子半句
I couldn't find a reference anywhere to a Half-Blood Prince.
- 那就是了，这事就算完了 - 费力斯！
- There we go。That settles it，then。- Filius！
我还想能在三把扫帚里找见你呢！
I was hoping to find you in the Three Broomsticks！
恐怕不行了，合唱团急训，霍拉斯
No，emergency choir practice，I'm afraid，Horace.
有人想喝黄油啤酒吗？
Does anyone fancy a Butterbeer？
我有个老伙计，在克拉克比山上滑雪
A chum of mine was sledging down Claxby Hill.
我们有辆自己造的，挪威风格的长雪橇
We had a very long，homemade，Norwegian-style sledge…
别，别去那边，到这边来
No，not there。Over here.
别坐对面，坐我旁边
No，sit beside me.
好了
Okay.
喝点什么？
Something to drink？
三杯黄油啤酒 我的那份放点姜汁，谢谢
Three Butterbeers，and some ginger in mine，please.
我靠
Oh，bloody hell.
是那个小白脸
Slick git.
罗恩，他们只是在牵牵小手
Honestly，Ronald，they're only holding hands.
又亲亲小嘴了
And snogging.
- 我得走了 - 怎么回事？
- I'd like to leave。- What？
你不会是认真的吧
You can't be serious.
- 那可是我妹妹 - 那又怎么了？
- That happens to be my sister。- So？
要是她转头看到你亲我怎么办？ 你想她会走开吗？
What if she looked over here and saw you snogging me？You expect her to leave？
- 嘿！ - 您好，教授，真高兴见到您
- Hey，my boy！- Hello，sir。Wonderful to see you.
我也是，我也是
And you，and you.
您来这做什么啊？
So，what brings you here？
三把扫帚和我的渊源说起来可就深了
The Three Broomsticks and I go way back，further than I care to admit.
我还记得当初 它叫一把扫帚时候的样子呢
I can remember when it was One Broomstick.
注意喽，格兰杰 这样，孩子，过去呢…
All hands on deck，Granger。Listen，my boy，in the old days…
我会偶尔举办几场晚宴
…I used to throw together the occasional supper party…
只邀请那么一两个学生
…for the select student or two.
- 你愿意来吗？ - 荣幸之至，教授
- Would you be game？- I'd consider it an honor，sir.
也欢迎你来，格兰杰
You would be welcome too，Granger.
- 太谢谢了，教授 - 好极了，等我的猫头鹰送信哦
- I'd be delighted，sir。- Splendid。Look for my owl.
真高兴见到你，华伦比 （彻底记错罗恩名字了）
Good to see you，Wallenby.
你这是玩的哪一手？
What are you playing at？
邓不利多让我多了解他
Dumbledore's asked me to get to know him.
- 了解他？ - 不晓得
- Get to know him？- I don't know.
这事一定很重要 要不然，邓不利多也不会让我去
It must be important。If it wasn't，Dumbledore wouldn't ask.
你嘴角有一点…
Got a little bit…
凯蒂，你都不知道这里装的是什么
Katie，you don't know what it could be.
- 哈利 - 什么事？
- Harry。- What？
她在酒吧里说的那段话，关于我俩亲亲的 你也听到了吧？
Did you hear what she said back at the pub about me and her snogging？
貌似
As if.
我警告过她的，让她别碰
I warned her。I warned her not to touch it.
别靠近，所有人，都退后
Don't get any closer。Get back，all of you.
除非包着，否则别碰，记住了吗？
Do not touch that，except by the wrappings。Do you understand？
你确定凯蒂进三把扫帚的时候
You're sure Katie did not have this in her possession…
没带着这个？
…when she entered the Three Broomsticks？
我说过了
It's like I said.
她去上厕所，回来之后就拿着那个包裹
She left to go to the loo，and when she came back she had the package.
她说，她要把包送到，事关重大
She said it was important that she deliver it.
- 她有没有说，要送到谁那儿？ - 邓不利多教授
- Did she say to whom？- To Professor Dumbledore.
很好，谢谢你，黎安，你先走吧
Very well。Thank you，Leanne。You may go.
为什么每次有什么事发生 总是你们在场？
Why is it when something happens it is always you three？
相信我，教授 我问自己这个问题问了都六年了
Believe me，professor，I've been asking myself the same question for six years.
哦，西弗勒斯
McGONAGALL：Oh，Severus.
你怎么看？
What do you think？
我看，贝尔小姐还能活着，真是幸运
I think Miss Bell is lucky to be alive.
她被下了恶咒，是不是？
She was cursed，wasn't she？
我知道凯蒂，在魁地奇球场之外的地方 她连只苍蝇都舍不得伤害
I know Katie。Off the pitch，she wouldn't hurt a fly.
就算她要把包裹交给邓不利多 也肯定不是有意识的
If she was delivering that to Dumbledore，she wasn't doing it knowingly.
她肯定是被下了恶咒
Yes，she was cursed.
是马尔福干的
It was Malfoy.
波特，这个指控非常严重
That is a very serious accusation，Potter.
的确
Indeed.
- 你有什么证据？ - 我就是知道
- Your evidence？- I just know.
你就是…
You just…
知道
…know.
你的天赋可真是了不得，波特
You astonish with your gifts，Potter.
你的天赋，凡人做梦也别想有
Gifts mere mortals can only dream of possessing.
多么伟大，你这救世主
How grand it must be to be the Chosen One.
我建议，你们都回宿舍去，所有人
I suggest you go back to your dormitories。All of you.
你觉得迪安看上金妮哪点了？
What do you suppose Dean sees in her？Ginny？
那金妮又看上他什么呢？
Well，what does she see in him？
迪安？他很聪明啊
Dean？He's brilliant.
不到五个小时之前，你还叫他小白脸
You called him a slick git not five hours ago.
那个，他那会不是对我妹妹动手动脚嘛
Yeah，well，he was running his hands all over my sister，wasn't he？
神经一绷，你就非恨他不可，懂不？ 那是原则问题
Something snaps，and you've gotta hate him，you know？On principle.
大概吧
I suppose.
- 那你说，他看上她什么了？ - 不晓得
- So，what is it he sees in her？- I don't know.
她聪明，有趣
She's smart，funny.
- 很迷人 - 迷人？
- Attractive。- Attractive？
- 就是，她皮肤很好啊 - 皮肤？
- You know，she's got nice skin。- Skin？
迪安跟我妹妹好，就因为她皮肤好？
Dean dates my sister because of her skin？
也不是啦，我只是说 这可能是原因之一
Well，no，I mean，I'm just saying it could be a contributing factor.
赫敏的皮肤也很好
Hermione's got nice skin.
你不觉得吗？就事论事来说的话
Wouldn't you say？As skin goes，I mean.
我真没想过这个问题
I've never really thought about it.
不过，我估计，是的吧
But，I suppose，yeah.
是很好
Very nice.
- 我该睡觉了 - 哦，对
- I think I'll be going to sleep now。- Right。Yeah.
说说吧，考迈克，最近 有没有见你叔叔贝卢斯啊？
So tell me，Cormac，do you see anything of your Uncle Tiberius these days？
有的，教授，实际上 这个假期，我该去和他…
Yes，sir。In fact，I'm meant to go hunting with him…
还有魔法部部长一起去打猎
…and the Minister for Magic over the holidays.
别忘了代我向他们二位问好
Well，be sure to give them both my best.
你叔叔呢，巴尔比？
What about your uncle，Belby？
以防有人没听说过，我介绍一下 马科斯的叔叔发明了狼毒药剂（防止狼人变身的药）
For those who don't know，Marcus' uncle invented the Wolfsbane Potion.
- 他最近有在搞什么新发明啊？ - 不晓得
- Is he working on anything new？- Don't know.
他和我爸关系不好，可能是因为 我爸说魔药都是垃圾
Him and Dad don't get on。Probably because me dad says potions are rubbish.
他说唯一有用的魔药 就是回家喝的几口烈酒
Says the only potion worth having is a stiff one at the end of the day.
你呢，格兰杰小姐？ 你父母在麻瓜的世界里哪里高就啊？
What about you，Miss Granger？What does your family do in the Muggle world？
我父母都是牙医
My parents are dentists.
给别人治牙齿
They tend to people's teeth.
太有趣了，这个职业危险吗？
Fascinating。And is that considered a dangerous profession？
不算是
No.
不过，是有个男孩，叫罗宾·芬克 咬了我爸爸一口
Although，one boy，Robbie Fenwick，did bite my father once.
害得他缝了十针
He needed 10 stitches.
啊，韦斯莱小姐，快请进
Ah。Miss Weasley。Come in，come in.
看她眼色，她跟迪安又吵架了
Look at her eyes。They've been fighting again，her and Dean.
抱歉，我一般不会迟到
Sorry。I'm not usually late.
没关系，来得正好，还能来点甜点 当然了，要是还没被巴尔比吃精光
No matter。You're just in time for dessert，that is，if Belby's left you any.
怎么回事？
What？
没什么
Nothing.
再见了，再见
Goodbye。Bye-bye.
- 波特 - 抱歉，教授
- Potter。- I'm sorry，sir.
我刚刚在欣赏您的沙漏
I was just admiring your hourglass.
哦，是啊
Oh，yes.
有趣的小玩意儿
A most intriguing object.
沙粒掉落的速度和谈话的质量相关
The sand runs in accordance with the quality of the conversation.
如果谈话有趣，沙粒就落得慢
If it is stimulating，the sand runs slowly.
- 如果无聊… - 我想我该走了
- If it is not… - I think I'll be going.
胡说，你有什么好怕的
Nonsense。You have nothing to fear，dear boy.
至于你的一些同学…
As to some of your classmates…
这么说吧，他们可上不了我的架子
…well，let's just say they're unlikely to make the shelf.
什么架子，教授？
The shelf，sir？
那些有抱负的学生，都希望想上那儿
Anyone who aspires to be anyone hopes to end up here.
不过话说回来，你已经是个人物了 不是吗，哈利？
But then again，you already are someone，aren't you，Harry？
伏地魔上过这个架子吗，教授？
Did Voldemort ever make the shelf，sir？
您认识他，对吧？ 汤姆·里德尔，您教过他
You knew him，didn't you，sir，Tom Riddle？You were his teacher.
里德尔在霍格沃兹的时候 有过很多老师
Mr。Riddle had a number of teachers whilst here at Hogwarts.
他那时候什么样？
What was he like？
抱歉，教授，恕我多问
I'm sorry，sir。Forgive me.
他杀死了我父母
He killed my parents.
当然
Of course.
你想多知道一些，可以理解
It's only natural you should want to know more.
不过恐怕我要让你失望了，哈利
But I'm afraid I must disappoint you，Harry.
我第一次见到里德尔，他虽然聪明…
When I first met Mr。Riddle，he was a quiet…
却很安静，一心想成为一流的巫师
…albeit brilliant，boy committed to becoming a first-rate wizard.
和我认识的其他学生并没有太大区别
Not unlike others I've known.
实际上，和你也没有多大区别
Not unlike yourself，in fact.
要说真有魔鬼…
If the monster existed…
他也藏得很深
…it was buried deep within.
好运，罗恩
Good luck，eh，Ron.
- 这帽子可真帅！ - 罗恩，衰人！
- Nice hat！- Ron，you're a loser.
我可指望你了，罗恩 我压了两加隆赌霍格沃兹赢呢
I'm counting on you，Ron。I have two Galleons on Gryffindor，yeah？
- 看起来不错啊，罗恩 - 衰人！
- Looking good，Ron。- Loser！
他戴的是什么玩意？
What's he wearing？
那个怎么样？
So how was it，then？
- 哪个怎么样？ - 你的聚会啊？
- How was what？- Your dinner party？
说真的，挺无聊的
Pretty boring，actually.
不过哈利应该挺喜欢那些点心
Though I think Harry enjoyed dessert.
斯拉格霍恩还要开圣诞舞会
Slughorn's having a Christmas do，you know.
我们可以带别人
And we're meant to bring someone.
我猜你会带麦克拉根去吧 他也是鼻涕虫俱乐部的，对不？
I expect you'll be bringing McLaggen。He's in the Slug Club，isn't he？
- 其实，本来我是想请你的 - 真的？
- Actually，I was going to ask you。- Really？
今天好运了，罗恩
Good luck today，Ron.
我知道你是最棒的
I know you'll be brilliant.
我要退队，今天比完就退 让麦克拉根接替吧
I'm resigning。After today's match，McLaggen can have my spot.
以后的事由你
Have it your way.
- 来点南瓜汁先？ - 好
- Juice？- Sure.
大家好啊
Hello，everyone.
你看上去糟透了，罗恩
You look dreadful，Ron.
是因为这个 你才往他杯子里放东西吗？
Is that why you put something in his cup？
那是补药吗？
Is it a tonic？
幸运水
Liquid luck.
别喝，罗恩
Don't drink it，Ron.
- 你这么干会被开除的 - 我可不知道你什么意思
- You could be expelled for that。- I don't know what you're talking about.
来吧，哈利，咱们还有比赛要赢呢！
Come on，Harry。We've got a game to win.
加油，罗恩！搞掂它！
Go on，Ron！Do it！
韦斯莱！
Weasley！Weasley！Weasley！
你真不该那么做
You really shouldn't have done it.
我知道，也许我该用混淆咒
I know。I suppose I could've just used a Confundus Charm.
那不一样，那是选拔，这是真正的比赛
That was different。That was tryouts。This was an actual game.
你没放
You didn't put it in.
罗恩只是以为我放了
Ron only thought you did.
咒语，我只是练练
Charms spell。I'm just practicing.
真厉害
Well，they're really good.
那是什么感觉，哈利？
How does it feel，Harry？
你看见迪安和金妮一起的时候？
When you see Dean with Ginny？
我都知道
I know.
从你看她的眼神
I see the way you look at her.
你是我最好的朋友
You're my best friend.
啊哦
Oops.
这个地方被人占了
I think this room's taken.
这些鸟是怎么回事？
What's with the birds？
万弹齐发
Oppugno.
那种感觉就是这样的
It feels like this.
她要是这么爱发神经，我也没办法
Look，I can't help it if she's got her knickers in a twist.
拉弗和我，我这么说吧 简直是停不下啊
What Lav and I have，well，let's just say，there's no stopping it.
传说中爱的化学反应
It's chemical.
我们会不会长久？谁知道呢？ 关键是，我可是自由身
Will it last？Who knows？Point is，I'm a free agent.
他想亲谁就亲谁
He's at perfect liberty to kiss whoever he likes.
我压根就不想管
I really couldn't care less.
之前我是不是误以为我和他 会一起出席斯拉格霍恩的圣诞晚会？
Was I under the impression he and I would be attending Slughorn's Christmas party？
没错
Yes.
如今，以眼下的情况看 我得另作一些安排了
Now，given the circumstances，I've had to make other arrangements.
你安排好了吗？
Have you？
嗯，怎么了？
Yes。Why？
我以为，既然我们两个 都没有理想的男女伴
I just thought，seeing as neither of us can go with who we'd really like to…
干脆就我们一起，以朋友的身份
…we should go together，as friends.
我之前怎么没想到？
Why didn't I think of that？
你跟谁一起去？
Who are you going with？
呃，惊喜
Um，it's a surprise.
总之，我们要担心的人是你 你不能随便带个人就去
Anyway，it's you we've got to worry about。You can't just take anyone.
看到那边的女孩子了吗？
See that girl over there？
罗米达·万尼，很显然 她想偷带迷魂药进学校
That's Romilda Vane。Apparently she's trying to smuggle you a love potion.
真的？
Really？
嘿！她对你感兴趣无非是因为 她以为你是所谓的救世主
Hey！She's only interested in you because she thinks you're the Chosen One.
可我确实是啊
But I am the Chosen One.
好了，抱歉，呃，开开玩笑
Okay，sorry。Um，kidding.
我会请我喜欢的人一起
I'll ask someone I like.
酷一些的
Someone cool.
我从没来过城堡的这个地方
I've never been to this part of the castle.
至少醒着的时候没有，我会梦游
At least not while awake。I sleepwalk，you see.
所以才穿鞋子上床
That's why I wear shoes to bed.
[咒语] 门户开启
Harmonia Nectere Passus.
来一杯？
Drink？
纳威
Neville.
我没能进鼻涕虫俱乐部
I didn't get into the Slug Club.
不过没关系 他还让巴尔比在厕所递毛巾呢
It's okay，though。He's got Belby handing out towels in the loo.
- 哦，不用了，谢谢 - 嗯
- Oh，well，I'm fine，mate。Thanks。- Okay.
赫敏，你在这干嘛？发生什么事了？
Hermione。What are you doing？And what happened to you？
我刚刚跑掉了 把考迈克丢在槲寄生下头
I've just escaped。I mean，left Cormac under the mistletoe.
考迈克？你请了他？
Cormac？That's who you invited？
我以为，这样最能惹罗恩不高兴
I thought it would annoy Ron the most.
谢谢，呆会再聊
Thank you。I'll catch up with you later.
他简直比贪吃根还多长了几根触角
He's got more tentacles than a Snarfalump plant.
- 来点龙肉干？ - 不用了，谢谢
- Dragon tartare？- No，I'm fine。Thank you.
也是，吃了这玩意口气重得不行
Just as well。They give one horribly bad breath.
我改主意了
On second thoughts…
这样或许能让考迈克保持距离
Might keep Cormac at bay.
哦，天，他过来了
Oh，God，here he comes.
我想她是去洗手间了
I think she just went to powder her nose.
你这朋友可真是个小泥鳅
Slippery little minx，your friend.
嘴巴也是一刻闲不下来，对吧
Likes to work her mouth too，doesn't she？
我吃的这什么啊？
What is this I'm eating，by the way？
龙蛋蛋
Dragon balls.
你刚刚给你自己 争取到了一个月的禁闭，麦克拉根
You've just bought yourself a month's detention，McLaggen.
别溜这么快，波特
Not so quick，Potter.
教授，我想我该回去找我的女伴了…
Sir，I really think I should rejoin the party。My date…
你少陪一两分钟，她也死不了
Can surely survive your absence for another minute or two.
再者，我只是来传个口信
Besides，I only wish to convey a message.
- 口信？ - 邓不利多教授
- A message？- From Professor Dumbledore.
让我代他问好，祝你聚会愉快
He asked me to give you his best，and he hopes you enjoy your holiday.
你也知道…
You see…
他出校了，得到新学期才回来
…he's traveling，and he won't return until term resumes.
出校，去哪？
Traveling where？
把你的手拿开，你个肮脏的哑炮！
Take your hands off me，you filthy Squib！
斯拉格霍恩教授
Professor Slughorn，sir.
我刚刚发现了这男孩 在楼上的走廊里游荡
I just discovered this boy lurking in an upstairs corridor.
他说，你邀请了他参加聚会
He claims to have been invited to your party.
好了好了，我不请自来，行了吧？
Okay，okay。I was gatecrashing。Happy？
我领他出去
I'll escort him out.
当然可以，教授
Certainly，professor.
好了，各位，继续
All right，everyone，carry on，carry on.
也许我是给那个叫贝尔的下了咒 也许我没有，关你什么事？
Maybe I did hex that Bell girl。Maybe I didn't。What's it to you？
我发过誓要保护你
I swore to protect you.
我立下了牢不可破的誓言
I made the Unbreakable Vow.
我不需要人保护
I don't need protection.
在这么多人当中，他只选了我，我！
I was chosen for this。Out of all others。Me.
- 我不会让他失望 - 你很害怕，德拉科
- And I won't fail him。- You're afraid，Draco.
你试图掩饰，但太明显了，让我帮你
You attempt to conceal it，but it's obvious。Let me assist you.
不！
No！
被他选中，这次的荣耀是我的！
I was chosen。This is my moment.
“牢不可破的誓言”
「Unbreakable Vow.」
你确定斯内普这么说的？
You're sure that's what Snape said？
肯定，怎么了？
Positive。Why？
你可不能违背牢不可破的誓言
Well，it's just you can't break an Unbreakable Vow.
这一层我自己就差不多想到了
I'd worked that much out for myself，funnily enough.
你不知道有多严重
You don't understand.
我靠
Oh，bloody hell.
我想你
I miss you.
真可爱
Lovely.
她成天就想亲我 我嘴唇都被亲干了，瞧
All she wants to do is snog me。My lips are getting chapped。Look.
你说就是了，我信
I'll take your word for it.
那后果会多严重？ 如果你违背了牢不可破的誓言？
So，what happens to you？What happens if you break an Unbreakable Vow？
你会死
You die.
布丁还在哦
Wait，the pudding's still here.
伏地魔给德拉科·马尔福 指派了一个任务？
Voldemort has chosen Draco Malfoy for a mission？
我知道听起来很疯狂
I know it sounds mad.
你有没有想过 斯内普只是假装要帮德拉科
Has it occurred to you Snape was simply pretending to offer Draco help…
从而套取情报？
…so he could find out what he was up to？
- 听起来不像 - 也许哈利没错
- That's not what it sounded like。- Perhaps Harry's right.
立牢不可破的誓言，是…
To make an Unbreakable Vow，it's…
归根结底，还是看你相不相信 邓不利多的判断
It comes down to whether or not you trust Dumbledore's judgment.
- 邓不利多信任斯内普，所以我也信 - 邓不利多也会犯错
- Dumbledore trusts Snape，therefore I do。- Dumbledore can make mistakes.
你是被仇恨蒙蔽了双眼
You're blinded by hatred.
- 我没有 - 你就是
- I'm not。- Yes，you are.
天天都有人失踪，哈利
People are disappearing，Harry，daily.
我们能信任的人也只剩寥寥几个
We place our trust in a handful of people.
如果现在内讧，我们就输定了
If we start fighting amongst ourselves，we're doomed.
张嘴
Open up，you.
不信任我吗？
Don't you trust me？
真好吃
It's good.
嗯…那个…啥
Yeah，I'll just… Get… Yeah.
- 来个派？ - 不用了
- Pie？- Not for me，no.
请你一定体谅莱姆斯
You'll have to forgive Remus.
他这种状况是有一些代价
It takes its toll，his condition.
你没事吧，韦斯莱先生？
Are you all right，Mr。Weasley？
我们被人跟踪
We're being followed，all of us.
大多数时候，莫利都不出门
Most days，Molly doesn't leave the house.
日子是不好过
It's not been easy.
你收到我的猫头鹰了吗？
Did you get my owl？
嗯，收到了
Yes，I did.
如果邓不利多出校了 那对魔法部来说肯定是新闻
If Dumbledore's traveling，then that's news to the Ministry…
不过，或许他就是想这样
…but perhaps that's the way Dumbledore wants it.
至于德拉科·马尔福
As for Draco Malfoy…
我倒是知道得多一点
…I know a bit more.
- 继续说 - 我派人去博金-博克
- Go on。- I sent an agent to Borgin and Burkes.
从你的描述来看，我想…
I think，from what you described…
夏天你和罗恩看到的…
…what you and Ron saw in summer…
那个让马尔福那么感兴趣的东西…
…the object that Draco is so interested in…
是一个消失柜
…is a vanishing cabinet.
消失柜？
A vanishing cabinet？
那是伏地魔刚得势时候流行的东西
They were all the rage when Voldemort first rose to power.
你可以想象它的吸引力 要是有食死徒找上门来
You can see the appeal。Should Death Eaters come knocking…
你只要躲进柜子里，消失上一两个小时
…one simply had to slip inside and disappear for an hour or two.
这些柜子能把你送到几乎任何一个角落
They can transport you anywhere.
不过这玩意可靠不大住，效果时有时无
Tricky contraptions though，very temperamental.
博金-博克那个怎么样了？
What happened to it？The one at Borgin and Burkes？
没怎样
Nothing.
还在那
It's still there.
晚饭真美味，莫利
It was delicious，Molly，really.
你们真不留下吗？
Are you sure you won't stay？
不了，该走了，月初第一天总是最难熬的
No，we should go。The first night of the cycle's always the worst.
莱姆斯？
Remus？
亲爱的
Sweetheart.
罗恩上床去了吗？
Has Ron gone to bed？
呃，还没吧
Um… Not yet。No.
鞋带松了
Shoelace.
圣诞快乐，哈利
Merry Christmas，Harry.
圣诞快乐
Merry Christmas.
- 哈利，别去！ - 莱姆斯！
- Harry，no！- Remus！
金妮！
Ginny！
我杀了小天狼星布莱克！
I killed Sirius Black！I killed Sirius Black！
你来抓我啊
You coming to get me？
哈利，你抓得到我吗？
Harry，can you get me？You coming to get me？
哈利？
Harry？
昏昏倒地！
Stupefy！
哈利！
Harry！
金妮
Ginny！
莫利
Molly.
他们要害你太容易了
It's easy for them to get to you.
你没死都是运气好 哈利，你该明白，你有多重要
You're bloody lucky you weren't killed。You have to realize who you are，Harry.
我知道，赫敏，好了吧？
I know who I am，Hermione，all right？
对不起
Sorry.
拉弗，我当然会戴了
Lav，come on。Of course I'll wear it.
这才是我的好恩恩
That's my Won-Won.
抱歉，我得去吐会
Excuse me，I have to go and vomit.
我很想知道，你是哪儿得到的消息
I'd like to know where you get your information.
你比多半的教工还消息灵通
More knowledgeable than half the staff，you are.
教授…
Sir…
梅乐思教授要退休了，是真的吗？
…is it true that Professor Merrythought is retiring？
哎呀，汤姆，我肯定不能 直接告诉你我知道，对不对？
Now，Tom。I couldn't tell you if I knew，could I？
还有，多谢你带来的菠萝 这确实是我的最爱
By the way，thank you for the pineapple。You're quite right，it is my favorite.
不过你是怎么知道的？
But how did you know？
直觉
Intuition.
天呀，都到点了吗？
Gracious。Is it that time already？
都回去吧，孩子们，要不然 迪佩特校长可要罚你们全关禁闭了
Off you go，boys，or Professor Dippet will have us all in detention.
赶快啊，汤姆，你可不想 在熄灯之后被人抓个正着吧
Look sharp，Tom。Don't want to be caught out of bed after hours.
- 有什么事吗，汤姆？ - 有，教授
- Is something on your mind，Tom？- Yes，sir.
是这样，我想不出还能找谁
You see，I couldn't think of anyone else to go to.
别的教授，他们不像你
The other professors，well，they're not like you.
他们或许会误解我
They might misunderstand.
继续说
Go on.
某天晚上我在图书馆
I was in the library the other night…
禁书区
…in the Restricted Section…
读到一些关于某种罕见魔法的材料
…and I read something rather odd about a bit of rare magic.
我想，您或许可以指点我
And I thought perhaps you could illuminate me.
要是我没记错，那个东西叫…
It's called，as I understand it…
你说什么？
I beg your pardon？
这种东西，我听都没听过 就算知道，也不会告诉你！
I don't know anything about such things，and if I did，I wouldn't tell you！
马上给我离开这里 以后也别再跟我提起这件事！
Now，get out of here at once，and don't let me ever catch you mentioning it again！
很困惑吧？
Confused？
你要是不觉得，我倒会很吃惊
I'd be surprised if you weren't.
我不明白，刚才那是怎么回事？
Well，I don't understand。What happened？
这或许是我所搜集的记忆中最重要的
This is perhaps the most important memory I've collected.
但这同时也是个谎言
It is also a lie.
这个记忆被篡改过
This memory has been tampered with…
就是被它的主人，我们的老朋友 斯拉格霍恩教授
…by the same person whose memory it is，our old friend，Professor Slughorn.
他为什么要改自己的记忆？
But why would he tamper with his own memory？
- 我猜，他是以此为耻 - 为什么？
- I suspect he's ashamed of it。- Why？
是啊，为什么？
Why，indeed？
我让你去接近斯拉格霍恩教授 你也办到了
I asked you to get to know Professor Slughorn，and you have done so.
接着，我想请你，劝他交出真实的记忆
Now I want you to persuade him to divulge his true memory…
无论你用什么办法都行
…any way you can.
我不是那么了解他，教授
I don't know him that well，sir.
这段记忆就是一切
This memory is everything.
没有它，我们无异于瞎子
Without it，we are blind.
没有它，我们只能 将这世界的命运拱手相让
Without it，we leave the fate of our world to chance.
你别无选择
You have no choice.
你不能失败
You must not fail.
我强烈建议各位重新温习
So I'd highly recommend you reacquaint yourself…
解药这一章
…with the chapter on antidotes.
下节课我们继续讲解牛粪石的神奇功效 现在下课
I'll tell you more about bezoars in our next class。Right，off you go.
啊哈，这不是我的小尾巴嘛
Alys，don't forget your rat tail.
啊哈，这不是我的魔药王子嘛
Aha。If it isn't the Prince of Potions himself.
有什么是我可以效劳的啊？
To what do I owe this pleasure？
教授，我能不能向您请教点事情
Sir，I wondered if I might ask you something.
尽管问吧，孩子，尽管问
Ask away，dear boy，ask away.
前几天晚上，我在图书馆的禁书区
The other day I was in the library，in the Restricted Section…
读到了一些关于某种罕见魔法的材料
…and I came across something rather odd about a very rare piece of magic.
嗯，那个东西叫什么？
Yes。And what was this rare piece of magic？
我记不大清楚了
Well，I don't know。I can't remember the name exactly.
所以我在想，是不是有些魔法 教授们是不能教学生的？
It got me wondering，are there some kinds of magic you're not allowed to teach us？
我只是魔药课老师，哈利
I'm Potions Master，Harry.
我想这个问题你最好还是问斯内普教授
I think your question'd better be posed to Professor Snape.
没错，呃
Yes。Um…
可是他跟我，看对方都不是很顺眼
He and I don't exactly see eye to eye，sir.
我的意思是
What I mean to say is…
他不像您
…well，he's not like you.
他会误解我
He might misunderstand.
是啊，没有黑暗哪里有光明
Yes。There can be no light without the dark.
魔法也是如此，而我 总是努力活在光明的一面
And so it is with magic。Myself，I always strive to live within the light.
我建议，你也这么做
I suggest you do the same.
汤姆·里德尔问您这个问题的时候 您也是这么回答他说的吗？
Is that what you told Tom Riddle，when he came asking questions？
邓不利多安排你来的，是不是？
Dumbledore put you up to this，didn't he？
是不是！？
Didn't he？
是
Yes？
哦，是你啊，波特
Oh，it's you，Potter.
抱歉，我现在很忙
I'm sorry，I'm busy at the moment.
真美，是不？这个月亮
It's beautiful，isn't it？The moon.
美极了
Divine.
好好享用了点睡前甜点，对不？
Had ourselves a little late-night snack，did we？
盒子就放在你床上 我想吃一颗也没大碍
It was on your bed，the box。I just thought I'd try one.
- 或者是吃20颗 - 我没有一刻不想她，哈利
- Or 20。- I can't stop thinking about her，Harry.
说实话，我还以为你觉得她烦了呢
Honestly，I reckoned she was annoying you.
她怎么可能会烦到我
She could never annoy me.
我想，我是爱上她了
I think I love her.
嗯，太好了
Well，brilliant.
你觉得她知道我的存在吗？
Do you think she knows I exist？
但愿吧，她和你都亲了三个多月嘴了
I hope so。She's been snogging you for three months.
亲嘴？你说谁啊？
Snogging？Who are you talking about？
你说的又是谁？
Who are you talking about？
当然是罗米达，罗米达·万尼
Romilda，of course。Romilda Vane.
哦，真好笑
Okay，very funny.
- 你干嘛？ - 这不是玩笑！我爱上她了！
- What was that for？- It's no joke！I'm in love with her！
好了，你爱上她了，可你见过她吗？
Fine，you're in love with her。Have you ever actually met her？
没，你能给我介绍吗？
No。Can you introduce me？
来，罗恩，我介绍 罗米达·万尼给你认识
Come on，Ron。I'm gonna introduce you to Romilda Vane.
抱歉，教授，如果不是绝对必要 我不会打搅您的
I'm sorry，sir。I wouldn't bother you if it weren't absolutely essential.
罗米达在哪？
Where's Romilda？
温比这是怎么了？
What's the matter with Wenby？
强效迷魂药
Very powerful love potion.
这样，扶他进来吧
Very well。Better bring him in.
我以为调配解药对你来说 是小菜一碟，哈利
I'd have thought you could whip up a remedy for this in no time，Harry.
我觉得这个还得经验丰富的高手来，教授
Well，I thought this called for a more practiced hand，sir.
亲爱的，想喝一杯吗？
Hello，darling。Fancy a drink？
或许你说得没错
Perhaps you're right.
还有，对不起，教授 关于之前的，那些误会
I'm sorry，by the way，professor，about earlier today，our misunderstanding.
哦，哪里哪里 过去的就让它过去吧，对吧？
Oh，not at all。All water under the bridge，you know？Correct？
我想这么多年，您都被问的厌烦了
I expect you're tired of it after all these years.
那些有关伏地魔的事情
All the questions about Voldemort.
别说那个名字
Don't use that name.
好了，大男孩，干光这杯
There you are，old boy。Bottoms up.
- 这是什么？ - 给你壮壮胆
- What's this？- Tonic for the nerves.
- 我怎么了？ - 迷魂药
- What happened to me？- Love potion.
还是强效的
A bloody strong one at that.
- 感觉糟透了 - 你得喝点提神的东西
- I feel really bad。- You need a pick-me-up.
我这里有黄油啤酒，葡萄酒 还有陈年的橡树蜜酒
Got Butterbeer，wine，dazzling oak-matured mead.
本来是另有他用的 不过，现在这个情况特殊…
I had other intentions for this，but I think，given the circumstances…
拿好了，波特
Here we are，Potter.
敬人生！
To life！
罗恩
Ron.
罗恩，教授，快想办法啊
Ron。Professor，do something.
我不明白
I don't understand.
加油啊，罗恩，呼吸
Come on，Ron，breathe.
那群女孩，要我命啊
These girls，they're gonna kill me.
脑子转得很快嘛，哈利，想得到用牛粪石 （传说中此物能解百毒）
Quick thinking on your part，Harry，using a bezoar.
你一定以教出这样的学生为傲吧，霍拉斯
You must be very proud of your student，Horace.
嗯？哦，是，是，很自豪
Hm？Oh，yes，very proud.
我们都同意，波特的行为很英勇
I think we agree，Potter's actions were heroic.
问题是，为什么会发生这种事？
The question is，why were they necessary？
是啊，为什么？
Why，indeed？
这酒看起来是份礼物，霍拉斯
This appears to be a gift，Horace.
你不记得是谁送给你的了？
You don't remember who gave you this bottle？
另外，这酒要是没被下毒
Which，by the way，possesses remarkably subtle hints of licorice and cherry…
甘草和樱桃的清香还是诱人的
…when not polluted with poison.
实际上，我本来是打算把这个送人的
Actually I had intended to give it as a gift myself.
我能问问，是送谁吗？
To whom，I might ask？
送给您，校长
To you，Headmaster.
他在哪？
Where is he？
我的小恩恩在哪？他有没有喊着要见我？
Where's my Won-Won？Has he been asking for me？
她来这干嘛？
What's she doing here？
我还想问你呢
I might ask you the same question.
我可是他女朋友
I happen to be his girlfriend.
我可是他…朋友
I happen to be his friend.
真是笑掉大牙 你们都好几星期没说话了
Don't make me laugh。You haven't spoken in weeks.
现在他有意思了，你就想和好啊
I suppose you want to make up now that he's all interesting.
他中毒了，你个蠢女人！
He's been poisoned，you daft dimbo！
还有，我一直都觉得他很有意思！
And for the record，I've always found him interesting.
哈，看到没？他感觉到我来了
Ah。See？He senses my presence.
没担心，小恩恩，我在这儿呢
Don't worry，Won-Won。I'm here.
我在这
I'm here.
呃…赫敏…
Uh… Hermione…
赫敏
Hermione.
哦，年轻真好，还能感受爱的伤害啊
Oh，to be young，and to feel love's keen sting.
好了，大家，都走吧
Well，come away，everybody.
韦斯莱先生有人照顾了
Mr。Weasley is well tended.
也是时候了，对吧？
About time，don't you think？
谢谢
Thank you.
别多话
Oh，shut up.
停下，罗恩，你又把这弄得满是雪花了
Stop it，Ron。You're making it snow.
再跟我过一遍，我是怎么 跟拉文德分手的来着？
Tell me how I broke up with Lavender again.
呃，是这样…
Um，well…
她来医院看你
…she came to visit you in the hospital.
然后你说了些话
And you talked.
说的也不是太多了
I don't believe it was a particularly long conversation.
别误会，能甩了她我高兴还来不及
Don't get me wrong，I'm bloody thrilled to be shot of her.
只是她看起来，好像要发飙
It's just she seems a bit put out.
确实啊，不是吗？
Yes，she does，doesn't she？
那天晚上之后的事情 你什么都不记得了？
You say you don't remember anything from that night？
一点都不记得？
Anything at all？
是有一些些
There is something.
不过没可能了 那会我正晕着呢，对吧？
But it can't be。I was completely boggled，wasn't I？
是啊，晕着
Right。Boggled.
哈利
Harry.
凯蒂回来了
That's Katie.
凯蒂·贝尔
Katie Bell.
凯蒂，你感觉怎么样？
Katie。How are you？
我知道你会问，哈利 但我真不知道是谁对我下的咒
I know you're going to ask，Harry，but I don't know who cursed me.
我真的很努力想回忆
I've been trying to remember，honestly.
可就是记不起来
But I just can't.
凯蒂？
Katie？
我知道是你干的好事，马尔福 是你对她下咒，对不对？
I know what you did，Malfoy。You hexed her，didn't you？
神锋无影！
Sectumsempra！
速速复原
Vulnera Sanentur.
你今天就得扔了它
You have to get rid of it。Today.
牵着我的手
Take my hand.
有求必应屋
The Room of Requirement.
我们要把混血王子的这本书…
We need to hide the Half-Blood Prince's book…
藏在一个谁也找不到的地方 包括你自己
…where no one will ever find it，including you.
- 什么声音？ - 什么声音？
- What was that？- What was that？
瞧？
See？
这里到处都是惊喜
You never know what you'll find up here.
好了，闭上眼睛 这样你才不会被诱惑
All right，close your eyes。That way you can't be tempted.
闭上眼睛
Close your eyes.
要是你愿意，这个吻 也可以变成藏在这里的秘密
That can stay hidden up here too，if you like.
你和金妮干完事了？
So did you and Ginny do it，then？
干什么？
What？
藏书啊
You know，hide the book？
哦，对
Oh，yeah.
哦，天，忘了点东西
Ah。Dear，yes.
斯拉格霍恩那边还是运气不佳？
Still no luck with Slughorn，then，I take it？
运气
Luck.
对了，我就是需要点运气
That's it。All I need's a bit of luck.
你感觉怎样？
Well，how do you feel？
好极了！
Excellent.
真的，太棒了！
Really excellent.
记住…
Remember…
斯拉格霍恩通常很早吃晚饭
…Slughorn usually eats early…
然后会散个步，之后就回办公室
…takes a walk，and then returns to his office.
嗯
Right.
- 我要去海格那 - 什么？
- I'm going down to Hagrid's。- What？
不行，哈利，你得去找斯拉格霍恩谈
No，Harry，you've got to go and speak to Slughorn.
- 我们都计划好了 - 我知道…
- We have a plan。- I know…
不过我觉得去海格那儿肯定有好事
…but I've got a good feeling about Hagrid's.
我觉得，我今晚就是该去那里 明白我的意思吗？
I feel it's the place to be tonight。Do you know what I mean？
- 不明白 - 好了，那就相信我吧，我知道自己在干什么
- No。- Well，trust me，I know what I'm doing.
至少福灵剂知道
Or Felix does.
梅林的胡子啊，是你，哈利！
Merlin's beard，Harry！
抱歉，教授，我本来该提示下 清清嗓子，咳嗽咳嗽之类的
Sorry，sir。I should've announced myself。Cleared my throat，coughed.
您大概以为我是斯普劳特教授吧
You probably feared I was Professor Sprout.
还真是，你怎么会这么想？
Yes，I did，actually。What makes you think that？
看您的样子就知道了，教授
Well，just the general behavior，sir.
这么偷偷摸摸了 看到我还会吓一大跳了
The sneaking around，the jumping when you saw me.
这些是毒须草叶吗，教授？ 这些可是很珍贵的，对吧？
Are those Tentacula leaves，sir？They're very valuable，aren't they？
要是找对买家，一片叶子能卖十加隆
Ten Galleons a leaf to the right buyer.
当然了，我对这种买卖根本不了解 只是听谣言罢了
Not that I'm familiar with any such transactions，but one does hear rumors.
我对这个的兴趣纯粹是学术性的
My own interests are purely academic，of course.
这些东西老是让我心里发毛
Personally，these plants always kind of freaked me out.
你怎么出城堡的，哈利？
How did you get out of the castle，Harry？
从大门出来的啊，教授
Through the front door，sir.
我去海格家，他是我的好朋友…
I'm off to Hagrid's。He's a very dear friend…
我这会想去拜访他一下
…and I fancied paying him a visit.
你要是不介意，我就先走了
So if you don't mind，I will be going now.
哈利！
Harry！
- 怎么了，教授？ - 这都快天黑了
- Sir？- It's nearly nightfall.
我不能让你一个人到处闲逛
Surely you realize I can't allow you to go roaming the grounds by yourself.
哦，这样啊，那您一起来吧
Well，then，by all means，come along，sir.
哈利，我坚持，你马上跟我
Harry，I must insist you accompany me…
回城堡去！
…back to the castle immediately！
那这一趟就白跑了，教授
That would be counterproductive，sir.
你这话什么意思？
And what makes you say that？
我也不知道
No idea.
霍拉斯
Horace.
梅林的胡子啊！这真是八眼巨蛛吗？
Merlin's beard。Is that an actual Acromantula？
我想是真的死蜘蛛，教授
A dead one，I think，sir.
我的天
Good God.
好家伙，你是怎么杀的它？
Dear fellow，however did you manage to kill it？
杀它？它可是我的老朋友
Kill it？Me oldest friend，he was.
- 抱歉，我不知道… - 别放心上，不止你一个人（不喜欢蜘蛛）
- I'm so sorry，I didn't… - Don't worry yourself，you're not alone.
蜘蛛这种生物，常常被人误解
Seriously misunderstood creatures，spiders are.
大概是因为眼睛吧，会让一些人害怕
It's the eyes，I reckon。They unnerve some folk.
还有那些长螯
Not to mention the pincers.
嗯，大概也是原因吧
Yeah，I reckon that too.
海格，我不想这个时候表现得铁石心肠
Hagrid，the last thing I wish to be is indelicate…
但八眼巨蛛的毒液可是相当稀罕
…but Acromantular venom is uncommonly rare.
能容我提取一两小瓶吗？
Would you allow me to extract a vial or two？
你也知道我，纯粹是用于学术研究
Purely for academic purposes，you understand.
反正它现在留着也没用了，不是吗？
Well，I don't suppose it's going to do him much good now，is it？
和我想的一模一样
My thoughts exactly.
我总是随身带几个安瓿瓶 就是为这种状况准备的
Always have a ampoule or two about my person for just such occasions as this.
魔药老师的老习惯了
Old Potions Master's habit，you know.
真希望你能见到它当年的样子
I wish you could've seen him in his prime.
雄伟极了，实在是雄伟极了
Magnificent，he was。Just magnificent.
哦，天
Oh，dear.
- 你愿意让我说几句悼词吗？ - 好吧
- Would you like me to say a few words？- Yes.
我想，它有家人吧？
He had a family，I trust？
哦，那可不
Oh，yeah.
永别了…
Farewell…
阿拉贡
Aragog.
永别了，阿拉贡
Farewell，Aragog…
蜘蛛之王，阿拉贡
…king of the arachnids.
你的肉体或将腐朽
Your body will decay…
但你的灵魂必将永存
…but your spirit lingers on.
如此，你的人类朋友们 才会在经久的悲恸中寻得一丝宽慰
And your human friends find solace in the loss they have sustained.
我把它从一个蜘蛛蛋开始养大 刚出壳的时候还是个小不点
I had him from an egg，you know。Tiny little thing he was when he hatched.
比只京巴狗大不了多少 你知道吧，京巴狗
No bigger than a Pekinese。A Pekinese，mind you.
真美好，我以前有一条鱼，叫弗兰西斯 跟我可亲了
How sweet。I once had a fish。Francis。He was very dear to me.
一天下午，我下楼一看，他就不见了
One afternoon I came downstairs，and he'd vanished.
“噗”，就不见了
Poof.
- 很奇怪啊，不是吗？ - 就是啊
- That's very odd，isn't it？- It is，isn't it？
不过，我想这就是人生吧
But that's life，I suppose.
你过着过着，突然，噗！就没了
You go along and then suddenly，poof！
- 噗 - 噗
- Poof。- Poof.
是个学生送我弗兰西斯的
It was a student who gave me Francis.
一个春日的午后 我看到我桌上有一口小碗
One spring afternoon I discovered a bowl on my desk…
里面是浅浅的一汪清水
…with just a few inches of clear water in it.
水面上，漂着一朵花瓣
And floating on the surface was a flower petal.
我正看着，它却沉了下去
As I watched，it sank.
就在要碰到碗底的时候
Just before it reached the bottom…
它变形了
…it transformed…
变成了一条小鱼
…into a wee fish.
真是美妙
It was beautiful magic.
赏心悦目
Wondrous to behold.
那瓣花是百合
The flower petal had come from a lily.
和你母亲一样美
Your mother.
我下楼的那天
The day I came downstairs…
那碗空了的那天
…the day the bowl was empty…
也就是你母亲…
…was the day your mother…
我知道你为什么在这
I know why you're here.
但我帮不了你
But I can't help you.
帮你会毁了我自己
It would ruin me.
你知道我是怎么幸存下来的吗，教授？
Do you know why I survived，professor？
在我留下这疤的那天晚上
The night I got this？
是因为她
Because of her.
因为她牺牲了自己
Because she sacrificed herself.
因为她不愿为了活命离开我
Because she refused to step aside.
因为她的爱比伏地魔的法力更强大
Because her love was more powerful than Voldemort.
- 别说他名字 - 我不怕说这个名字，教授
- Don't say his name。- I'm not afraid of the name，professor.
我告诉您一些事情吧
I'm going to tell you something.
一些别人只是猜测的事情
Something others have only guessed at.
传说是真的
It's true.
我是救世主
I am the Chosen One.
只有我能打败他，但是在这之前…
Only I can destroy him，but in order to do so…
我必须知道 汤姆·里德尔问了您什么问题
…I need to know what Tom Riddle asked you years ago in your office…
我必须知道，您告诉了他什么
…and I need to know what you told him.
勇敢些，教授
Be brave，professor.
像我妈妈一样，勇敢些
Be brave like my mother.
否则，您只能给她蒙羞
Otherwise，you disgrace her.
否则，她的死毫无价值
Otherwise，she died for nothing.
否则，您心里的碗会永远空着
Otherwise，the bowl will remain empty forever.
请你，看完这个之后，不要看低我
Please，don't think badly of me when you see it.
即使在当时，你也没法想象他的强大
You've no idea what he was like，even then.
前几天晚上我在图书馆
I was in the library the other night…
禁书区
…in the Restricted Section…
我读到一些关于某种罕见魔法的材料
…and I read something rather odd about a bit of rare magic.
如果没记错，那东西叫…
It's called，as I understand it…
魂器
…a Horcrux.
- 你说什么？ - 魂器
- I beg your pardon？- Horcrux.
我看书的时候，看到这个词
I came across the term while reading…
但不是很懂
…and I didn't fully understand it.
汤姆，我不知道你在看的是什么书
I'm not sure what you were reading，Tom…
但这是非常黑暗邪恶的东西，非常邪恶
…but this is very dark stuff，very dark indeed.
正因此…
Which is…
我才来找您
…why I came to you.
魂器，是一种容器，隐藏着一个人的灵魂
A Horcrux is an object in which a person has concealed part of their soul.
但我想不出，怎么才办到的，教授
But I don't understand how that works，sir.
一个人把灵魂分裂出一部分 藏在一个容器里
One splits one's soul and hides part of it in an object.
这样，即使肉体遭到攻击甚至被毁 他仍被保护着
By doing so，you're protected，should you be attacked and your body destroyed.
保护？
Protected？
那部分隐藏起来的灵魂会存活下去
That part of your soul that is hidden lives on.
换言之，就是长生不死
In other words，you cannot die.
那要怎么做才能分裂出灵魂，教授？
And how does one split his soul，sir？
我想，你已经知道答案了吧，汤姆
I think you already know the answer to that，Tom.
杀戮
Murder.
对
Yes.
杀戮会令灵魂分离 这是对自然法则的违背
Killing rips the soul apart。It is a violation against nature.
你只能把灵魂分出来一次吗？ 比如，能不能分七次…？
Can you only split the soul once？For instance，isn't seven…
七次？
Seven？
梅林的胡子啊，汤姆 难道杀一个人还不够可怕吗？
Merlin's beard，Tom。Isn't it bad enough to consider killing one person？
要是把灵魂分成七份…
To rip the soul into seven pieces…
这些都只是假设，对吧，汤姆？ 纯粹是学术探讨？
This is all hypothetical，isn't it，Tom？All academic？
那是自然，教授
Of course，sir.
就当这是我们之间的小秘密
It'll be our little secret.
教授
Sir.
比我想象的还要糟糕
This is beyond anything I imagined.
您是说，他成功了？ 他做出了一个魂器？
You mean to say he succeeded，sir，in making a Horcrux？
是的，他成功了，但不止是一个
Oh，yes，he succeeded，all right。And not just once.
那些到底是什么东西？
What are they exactly？
什么都有可能，可能是最不起眼的物件
Could be anything。Most commonplace of objects.
比如，戒指
A ring，for example.
或者，笔记本
Or a book.
- 汤姆·里德尔的日记 - 没错，这就是一个魂器
- Tom Riddle's diary。- It's a Horcrux，yes.
四年前，你在密室救了金妮之后…
Four years ago，when you saved Ginny's life…
把这个带给我
…in the Chamber of Secrets，you brought me this.
我就知道这种魔法不一般
I knew this was a different kind of magic.
非常邪恶，非常强大 但直到今晚，我才知道它到底有多强大
Very dark，very powerful。But until tonight I had no idea just how powerful.
- 那这戒指？ - 是伏地魔母亲的
- The ring？- Belonged to Voldemort's mother.
极难找到，但更难摧毁
Difficult to find。Even more difficult to destroy.
但是，如果谁能 把那些魂器全部找到并且销毁
But if you could find them all，if you did destroy each Horcrux…
谁就可能消灭伏地魔
One destroys Voldemort.
可怎么找呢？他可能把这些藏在任何地方
But how would you find them？They could be hidden anywhere.
没错，但魔法，尤其是黑魔法
True。But magic，especially dark magic…
会留下踪迹
…leaves traces.
您这些天就是去这些地方 是不是，教授？
It's where you've been going，isn't it，sir？
- 就是您不在学校的时候？ - 对
- When you leave the school？- Yes.
我想，我可能又找到了一个
And I think perhaps I may have found another.
但这次，我没法一个人销毁它
But this time，I cannot hope to destroy it alone.
哈利，我这次对你要求又太过分了
Once again，I must ask too much of you，Harry.
你有没有想过你的要求太过分了…
Have you ever considered that you ask too much…
你把太多事当成理所应当的了？
…that you take too much for granted？
你那智慧的大脑，有没有想过 我不想再继续做这件事了？
Has it ever crossed your brilliant mind that I don't want to do this anymore？
我有没有想过，与此事无关
Whether it has or hasn't is irrelevant.
没有商量的余地了，西弗勒斯 你已经同意，没什么好谈的了
I will not negotiate with you，Severus。You agreed。Nothing more to discuss.
哦，哈利
Oh，Harry.
你该刮刮胡子了，朋友
You need a shave，my friend.
知道嘛，有时候 我都忘了你成长了这么多
You know，at times，I forget how much you've grown.
有时候，我还是能看到 那个壁橱里的小男孩
At times，I still see the small boy from the cupboard.
原谅我这番无病呻吟，哈利
Forgive my mawkishness，Harry.
我是个老头了
I'm an old man.
在我看来您一点没变，教授
You still look the same to me，sir.
你和你母亲一样，总是这么好心肠
Just like your mother，you're unfailingly kind.
恐怕，没人会忽视这一点
A trait people never fail to undervalue，I'm afraid.
我们今晚要去的地方，极度凶险
The place to which we journey tonight is extremely dangerous.
我答应过你，让你随我去 我不会食言
I promised you could accompany me，and I stand by that promise.
但有一个条件
But there is one condition：
你必须毫不犹豫得执行我所有指示
You must obey every command I give you，without question.
好的，教授
Yes，sir.
你明白我的意思吧？
You do understand what I'm saying？
我若是让你躲，你就躲
Should I tell you to hide，you hide.
我若是让你跑，你就跑
Should I tell you to run，you run.
我若是让你别管我，救自己，你也必须照做
Should I tell you to abandon me and save yourself，you must do so.
我要你保证，哈利
Your word，Harry.
我保证
My word.
扶着我手臂
Take my arm.
教授，我们在霍格沃兹内 好像不能幻影移形吧？
Sir，I thought you couldn't Apparate within Hogwarts.
呵呵，当校长自然有当校长的好处
Well，being me has its privileges.
就是这儿了
This is the place.
错不了
Oh，yes.
有人在这里施过魔法
This place has known magic.
- 教授！ - 要想找到入口
- Sir！- In order to gain passage…
必须付出代价
…payment must be made.
一个能削弱来者实力的代价
Payment intended to weaken any intruder.
- 您该让我来，教授 - 不行，哈利
- You should've let me，sir。- No，Harry.
你的血比我的珍贵太多了
Your blood's much more precious than mine.
伏地魔不会轻易让人发现 他隐藏灵魂的地方
Voldemort will not have made it easy to discover his hiding place.
他一定会布下防范
He will have put certain defenses in position.
小心
Careful.
就是那儿了
There it is.
问题是，我们怎么过去？
The only question is，how do we get there？
劳驾帮个忙，哈利
If you would，Harry.
您认为魂器就在这里吗？
Do you think the Horcrux is in there，sir？
嗯，没错
Oh，yes.
必须喝光这些液体
It has to be drunk.
一点不剩
All of it has to be drunk.
你还记得，我带你来之前 说的那个条件吗？
You remember the conditions on which I brought you with me？
这些液体，或许会让我失去行动能力
This potion might paralyze me.
或许会让我忘记我来这里的目的
Might make me forget why I'm here.
或许会让我无比痛苦 痛苦到令我向你哀求
Might cause me so much pain that I beg for relief.
但你不要理会我的任何要求
You are not to indulge these requests.
这是你的使命，哈利 确保我喝光这些液体
It's your job，Harry，to make sure I keep drinking this potion.
就算是要逼着我下咽，你也要做
Even if you have to force it down my throat.
- 明白了吗？ - 可是教授，为什么不让我喝？
- Understood？- Why can't I drink it，sir？
因为我比你老，比你聪明 而你比我珍贵太多
Because I am much older，much cleverer，and much less valuable.
祝你健康，哈利
Your good health，Harry.
教授
Professor.
教授！
Professor！
哈利
Harry.
教授，你听得到我吗？
Professor，can you hear me？
教授
Professor.
别，不要
No。Don't.
您一定要继续喝，您自己说的，记得吗？
You have to keep drinking，like you said。Remember？
- 停下 - 会停下的，会停下的
- Stop。- It will stop。It will stop…
- 但您得先继续喝 - 求你，别逼我
- …but only if you keep drinking。- Please，don't make me.
- 对不起，教授 - 求求你
- I'm sorry，sir。- Please.
- 杀了我吧，杀了我吧！- 不！
- Kill me。Kill me！- No！
是我的错
It's my fault.
都是我的错
It's all my fault.
是我的错
It's my fault.
再喝一杯，教授，就一杯 喝完之后，我保证
Just one more，sir。One more，and then I promise…
我保证，您说什么我都会去做
…I promise I'll do what you say.
- 我保证 - 不要
- I promise。- No.
求您了
Please.
哈利
Harry.
水
Water.
您成功了，教授
You did it，sir.
您看
Look.
哈利
Harry.
水
Water.
清水如泉
Aguamenti.
水
Water.
荧光闪烁
Lumos.
球状荧光！
Lumos Maxima！
哈利
Harry.
神锋无影！
Sectumsempra！
哈利
Harry.
- 昏昏倒地！ - 哈利
- Stupefy！- Harry.
哈利
Harry.
烈火熊熊！
Partis Temporus！
都回自己的学院去，别闲逛
Go to your houses。No dawdling.
我们得去校医院，教授 去找庞弗雷夫人
We need to get you to the hospital wing，sir，to Madam Pomfrey.
不
No.
西弗勒斯，我需要西弗勒斯
Severus。Severus is who I need.
去叫醒他，告诉他发生了什么
Wake him。Tell him what happened.
别跟其他人提起
Speak to no one else.
找西弗勒斯，哈利
Severus，Harry.
快躲到楼下，哈利
Hide yourself below，Harry.
没我允许，不要出声 也不要被别人看到
Don't speak or be seen by anybody without my permission.
无论发生了什么，都要记得 在下面躲好
Whatever happens，it's imperative you stay below.
哈利，照我说的做
Harry，do as I say.
相信我
Trust me.
晚安啊，德拉科
Good evening，Draco.
晚上天气这么好 你来这儿做什么啊？
What brings you here on this fine spring evening？
还有谁在这？我听到你和人说话了
Who else is here？I heard you talking.
我常常一个人自言自语 这习惯可相当有益
I often talk aloud to myself。I find it extraordinarily useful.
你会自言自语吗，德拉科？
Have you been whispering to yourself，Draco？
德拉科…
Draco…
- 你不会杀人的 - 你怎么知道我会什么不会什么？
- You are no assassin。- How do you know what I am？
我做过很多事，说出来吓死你
I've done things that would shock you.
给凯蒂·贝尔下咒，想让她把项链送给我？
Like cursing Katie Bell and hoping that in return she'd bear a cursed necklace to me？
偷换了瓶掺了毒物的蜜酒？ 诸如此类的事情？
Replacing a bottle of mead with one laced with poison？
恕我直言，德拉科
Forgive me，Draco.
你的这些尝试太不用心了
I cannot help feeling these actions are so weak…
说明你的心思完全没有放在这里
…your heart can't really have been in them.
他信任我，我被选中了
He trusts me。I was chosen.
那，我就成全你吧
Then I shall make it easy for you.
除你武器！
Expelliarmus！
很好，很好
Very good。Very good.
你不是一个人在这
You're not alone.
还有其他人
There are others.
怎么办到的？
How？
有求必应屋里的消失柜
The vanishing cabinet in the Room of Requirement.
- 我一直在修理它 - 我猜猜看
- I've been mending it。- Let me guess.
它还有个姐妹柜，双子柜
It has a sister。A twin.
放在博金-博克，两个形成了一条通道
In Borgin and Burkes。They form a passage.
真天才
Ingenious.
德拉科
Draco…
很多年前，我认识的一个孩子 他人生的每一个抉择都做错了
…years ago，I knew a boy who made all the wrong choices.
- 如今，让我帮你一次吧 - 我不用你帮！
- Please let me help you。- I don't want your help！
你还不明白吗？我必须这么做
Don't you understand？I have to do this.
我必须杀了你
I have to kill you.
要不然他就会杀我
Or he's gonna kill me.
瞧我们逮着谁了
Well，look what we have here.
干得好，德拉科
Well done，Draco.
晚上好啊，贝拉特里克斯
Good evening，Bellatrix.
我看你该给我介绍一下这几位吧？
I think introductions are in order，don't you？
我也想，阿不思，可惜今天时间有点紧
Love to，Albus，but I'm afraid we're all on a bit of a tight schedule.
动手
Do it.
他根本没那胆子，跟他爹一样
He doesn't have the stomach，just like his father.
还是用我的办法来吧
Let me finish him in my own way.
不！黑魔王的命令很明白 必须让马尔福下手
No！The Dark Lord was clear，the boy is to do it.
这是你荣耀，快动手
This is your moment。Do it.
快啊，德拉科
Go on，Draco.
就现在！
Now！
不
No.
西弗勒斯
Severus.
求求你…
Please.
阿瓦达索命
Avada Kedavra.
海格！你躲哪了？
Hagrid！Hello？
斯内普！他信任你！
Snape！He trusted you！
你们走
Go on.
速速禁锢
Incarcerous.
还手啊！你这懦夫，还手！
Fight back！You coward，fight back！
不！他是黑魔王的猎物
No！He belongs to the Dark Lord.
神锋无影！
Sectumsempra！
你竟敢拿我发明的魔咒来对付我，波特？
You dare use my own spells against me，Potter？
没错
Yes.
我就是混血王子
I'm the Half-Blood Prince.
波特
McGONAGALL：Potter…
刚才发生的那些事
…in light of what has happened…
你应该找人谈谈
…if you should have the need to talk to someone…
你该知道，邓不利多教授
You should know，Professor Dumbledore…
你对他来说，很重要
…you meant a great deal to him.
你觉得他下得了手吗？
Do you think he would've done it？
德拉科？
Draco？
不会
No.
不会，他已经准备放下魔杖了
No，he was lowering his wand.
到头来，还是斯内普
In the end，it was Snape.
总是斯内普
It was always Snape.
而我却什么也做不成
And I did nothing.
这个是假的
It's fake.
打开吧
Open it.
“致黑魔王：我知道 你读到这封信时，我早已死了
「To the Dark Lord。I know I will be dead long before you read this…
但我想让你知道，是我 发现了你的秘密
but I want you to know that it was I who discovered your secret.
我拿走了真的魂器，并将尽快销毁
I have stolen the real Horcrux and intend to destroy it as soon as I can.
我以死为代价，希望当你遇到敌手时
I face death in the hope that when you meet your match…
你会是个血肉之躯的凡人
you will be mortal once more.
R.A.B.”
R.A.B.「
R.A.B.
不知道是谁
Don't know.
但不管他们是谁，真的魂器在他们手上
But whoever they are，they have the real Horcrux.
我们做的这一切，都是枉然
Which means it was all a waste.
一切的一切
All of it.
罗恩不介意了
Ron's okay with it，you know.
关于你跟金妮的事
You and Ginny.
不过我要是你，有他在场的时候 还是能少亲就少亲
But if I were you，when he's around，I'd keep the snogging to a minimum.
我不会回来了，赫敏
I'm not coming back，Hermione.
无论邓不利多开始的是什么使命 我都要去完成它
I've got to finish whatever Dumbledore started.
我也不知道这条路会引我去向何方
And I don't know where that'll lead me…
但如果可能，我会让你和罗恩 知道我到了什么地方
…but I'll let you and Ron know where I am when I can.
我一直很佩服你的勇气，哈利
I've always admired your courage，Harry.
但有时候，你也太傻气了
But sometimes，you can be really thick.
你不会真以为靠你一个人
You don't really think you're going to be able…
就能找到所有魂器吧？
…to find all those Horcruxes by yourself，do you？
你需要我们，哈利
You need us，Harry.
我从没注意过，原来这里的风景这么美
I never realized how beautiful this place was.